Art Buchwald Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Art Buchwald Papers 1885-2007 1962-2000
MSS86197
Buchwald, Art, 1925-2007
83,000 items
236 containers plus 22 oversize
99 linear feet
4,084 digital files (42.27 GB)
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Humorist, political commentator, and playwright. Correspondence, columns, book manuscripts, speeches, plays, screenplays, biographical material, photographs, audiovisual material, digital files, posters, memorabilia, drawings, appointment calendars, address books, artifacts, copyright registration and renewals, legal documents, financial records, and clippings documenting Buchwald's career as a columnist and his personal life.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Bernheim, Alain--Correspondence.; Bernheim, Alain--Trials, litigation, etc.; Bradlee, Benjamin C.--Correspondence.; Buchwald family--Correspondence.; Buchwald family.; Buchwald, Art--Death and burial.; Buchwald, Art--Friends and associates--Correspondence.; Buchwald, Art--Trials, litigation, etc.; Buchwald, Art.; Buchwald, Art. I'll always have Paris: a memoir. 1996.; Buchwald, Art. King for a day. 1982.; Buchwald, Art. Leaving home: a memoir. 1993.; Buchwald, Art. No love atoll. 1948.; Buchwald, Art. Sheep on the runway. 1970.; Buchwald, Art. Too soon to say goodbye. 2006.; Graham, Katharine, 1917-2001--Correspondence.; Hackney, Lucy D.--Correspondence.; Hackney, Sheldon, 1933-2013--Correspondence.; Hix, Al--Correspondence.; Kennedy family--Correspondence.; Landers, Ann--Correspondence.; Manning, Gordon, 1917-2006--Correspondence.; Starling, Florence Leola, 1922-2014--Correspondence.; Wolper, David L.--Correspondence.
Organizations
Hebrew Orphan Asylum of New York.; New York Herald Tribune (Firm); Paramount Pictures Corporation--Trials, litigation, etc.; United States. Marine Corps.; University of Southern California.
Subjects
American newspapers--Washington (D.C.); American wit and humor.; Americans--France--Paris.; Authors--Correspondence.; Breach of contract--United States.; Charities.; Children--Institutional care--New York (State); Depression, Mental.; Entertainers--Correspondence.; Hospice care--United States.; Humorists, American--Biography.; Journalism--Europe.; Journalism--France--Paris.; Journalism--United States.; Journalism--Washington (D.C.); Journalists--Correspondence.; Mental health.; Motion pictures--Plots, themes, etc.; Musicians--Correspondence.; Newspapers--Sections, columns, etc.--Humor.; Newspapers--Sections, columns, etc.--Social aspects.; Politicians--Correspondence.; Radio programs--United States.; Wit and humor--Congresses.; Wit and humor.; World War, 1939-1945--United States.
Places
Georgetown (Washington, D.C.)--Social life and customs.; Martha's Vineyard (Mass.)--Social life and customs.; Paris (France)--Social life and customs.; Washington (D.C.)--Social life and customs.
Titles
Coming to America (Motion picture); On Buchwald (Radio program); Washington post.
Occupations
Humorists.; Playwrights.; Political commentators.
Provenance
The papers of Art Buchwald, humorist, political commentator, and playwright were purchased by the Library of Congress from Joel and Tamara Buchwald in 2017.
Additional Description
A partial list of significant correspondents found in the General Correspondence: VIP Chronological file is appended to this finding aid as Appendix A.
A small portion of Buchwald's word-processing disks are inventoried by file name and type (i.e. column, speech, letter). A searchable PDF copy of this inventory is appended to this finding aid as Appendix B.
Transfers
Video cassettes, audio cassettes, and reels featuring interviews, speeches, and recordings of Buchwald's radio show, Buchwald On: The Art Buchwald Radio Program, have been transferred to the Motion Picture, Broadcasting, and Recorded Sound Division where they are identified as part of the Art Buchwald Papers.
Photographs of Buchwald, his family, and friends, especially the Kennedy family and those who also lived in Martha's Vineyard, Massachusetts, as well as many notable cartoonists' depictions of Buchwald have been transferred to the Prints and Photographs Division where they are identified as part of the Art Buchwald Papers.
Patrons are encouraged to contact these divisions in advance of a research visit.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of Art Buchwald are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Digital Format
Digital files were received as part of the Art Buchwald Papers on a variety of storage media, each of which was assigned a unique digital ID number. Use the digital ID number to request access copies of the files. Access to digital content is available onsite only in the Manuscript Reading Room and requires advance notice. Consult reference staff in the Manuscript Division for more information.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1925, Oct. 20 Born, Mount Vernon, N.Y.
1942 1945 United States Marine Corps, 4th Marine Aircraft Wing
1945 1948 Attended the University of Southern California, Los Angeles, Calif.
1948 Moved to Paris, France Stringer, Variety magazine
1949 Columnist, New York Herald Tribune
1950 Published Paris After Dark. Paris: Imprimerie du Centre
1952 Married Ann McGarry (died 1994)
1962 Moved to Washington, D.C.
1962 2006 Syndicated columnist
1980 Published with Ann Buchwald, Seems Like Yesterday. New York: G.P. Putnam's Sons
1982 Received Pulitzer Prize for Commentary
1986 Elected to the American Institute of Arts and Letters Received National Press Club's Fourth Estate Award
1993 Published Leaving Home. New York: G.P. Putnam's Sons
1996 Published I'll Always Have Paris. New York: G.P. Putnam's Sons
2000 Published Stella in Heaven: Almost a Novel. New York: G.P. Putnam's Sons
2006 Published Too Soon to Say Goodbye. New York: G.P. Putnam's Sons
2007, Jan. 17 Died, Washington, D.C.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Art Buchwald (1925-2007) span the years 1885 to 2007, with the bulk of the material dating from 1962 to 2000. The collection documents Buchwald’s career as a humorist and columnist, as well as many aspects of his personal life and relationships. The papers are organized into nine series: General Correspondence, Writings, Buchwald v. Paramount Pictures Corporation, Administrative File, Speeches, Personal File, Subject File, Digital File, and Oversize.
The collection extensively documents Buchwald’s work as a syndicated columnist in Europe (1949-1962) and the United States (1962-2006), as well as his work as an author, playwright, and public speaker. These papers primarily focus on Buchwald’s professional pursuits, especially his years in Washington, D.C., while working for the Washington Post, though evidence of his personal relationships with entertainers, political figures, print and broadcast journalists, musicians, literary figures, friends, and family members form a significant part of the collection. These papers further illustrate the many connections Buchwald made during his life in Paris, France, Washington, D.C., and summers in Martha’s Vineyard, Massachusetts. Buchwald’s papers also broadly chronicle his youth and include material related to his childhood in the Hebrew Orphan Asylum and New York City’s foster care system, service in the United States Marine Corps during World War II, education at the University of Southern California, and his efforts to establish himself as a writer in Paris in the late 1940s and 1950s. Buchwald’s illnesses later in life, stay in hospice care, and death in 2007 are also documented in this collection. To a lesser extent, these papers reflect Buchwald’s lifelong struggle with depression. Though more minimally documented, this marks an important aspect of Buchwald’s life and character.
The collection’s series are listed and briefly described below. A fuller description of each series and a list of its contents can be accessed in the series descriptions within the container list.
The General Correspondence series is composed primarily of incoming letters Buchwald received from friends, colleagues, and relatives. The series is organized into three major groupings: VIP, Close friends, and Chronological. The “VIP” and “Close friends” designations were maintained as received and include letters from a wide variety of notable political and public figures.
The Writings series forms the largest portion of the collection and documents Buchwald’s work as a columnist, novelist, autobiographer, and playwright and documents his many articles, books, columns, memoirs, plays, and screenplays.
The Buchwald v. Paramount Pictures Corporation series chronicles a lawsuit Buchwald and producer, Alain Bernheim, filed against Paramount Pictures in 1988 for breach of contract in the development of a treatment for the film Coming to America.
The Administrative File largely pertains to Buchwald’s career management, finances, and public persona.
The Speeches series documents events and engagements for which Buchwald served as a speaker or master of ceremonies, was honored, or attended and includes remarks and scheduling information related to his many appearances at events, conferences, conventions, organizational meetings, charity benefits, award banquets, and commencements.
The Personal File chronicles Buchwald’s childhood in foster care in New York City, service in the United States Marine Corps during WWII, education at the University of Southern California, early career in Paris, France, family, health, and death.
The Subject File holds a wide range of files pertaining to Buchwald’s personal interests, organizations and charities he supported, and organizations in which Buchwald was indirectly or directly involved, among other topics.
The Digital File series contains the contents of a personal computer and word-processing disks created and used by Buchwald between 1987 and 2006.
The remaining series houses Oversize and unusually formatted material.
Arrangement of the Papers
This collection is arranged in nine series:
General Correspondence, 1947-2007
Writings, 1948-2006
Buchwald v. Paramount Pictures Corporation, 1981-1999
Administrative File, 1953-2006
Speeches, 1959-2006
Personal, 1885-2007
Subject File, 1952-2006
Digital File, 1987-2006
Oversize, 1925-2007
Container List
- General Correspondence, 1947-2007 (Box 1-48)
  The General Correspondence series is composed primarily of incoming letters Buchwald received from friends, colleagues, and relatives. The series is organized into three groupings: VIP, Close friends, and Chronological. The “VIP” and “Close friends” designations were maintained as received and include letters from a wide variety of notable political and public figures. The VIP grouping is further arranged into an alphabetical file and a chronological file. Correspondents represented in the VIP alphabetical file include Alain Bernheim, Benjamin C. Bradlee, Katharine Graham, Ann Landers, Gordon Manning, Florence Leola Starling, David L. Wolper, members of the Kennedy family, several cartoonists, and members of Congress, among others. The VIP chronological file also contains letters from many notable figures. Appendix A contains a partial list of significant correspondents found in the VIP chronological file. Al Hix and Lucy D. and Sheldon Hackney, among others, appear in the Close friends file. Though efforts were made to reduce overlap of correspondents across groupings, names may appear in more than one of the groupings in this series.
  Letters across the General Correspondence series are largely personal in nature and chronicle Buchwald’s relationships with entertainers, political figures, print and broadcast journalists, musicians, literary figures, and friends. This series broadly reflects Buchwald's many circles of friends, especially those associated with Paris, Washington, D.C., and Georgetown specifically, summers in Martha's Vineyard, and Hollywood, as well as others working in the news industry. Topics covered vary based on the correspondent, but many letters detail life in Paris, time in the United States Marine Corps, shared personal history or acquaintances, projects and events in which Buchwald participated, and responses to his columns and books. The humor shared between Buchwald and his friends is well documented in this series.
  Arranged into three groupings: VIP, Close friends, and Chronological and arranged alphabetically by name or chronologically therein.
  - VIP (Box 1)
    - Alphabetical (Box 1)
      - Bacall, Lauren, 1957-1958, 1969-1985 (Box 1)
      - Baker, Russell, 1966-2002, (2 folders) (Box 1)
      - Barry, Dave, 1990-1998, undated (Box 1)
      - Bernheim, Alain, 1956-1991, undated, (9 folders) (Box 1)
      - Block, Herbert, 1966-1972, 1984, 1991-2001, undated (Box 1)
      - Bombeck, Erma (Box 1)
        - Correspondence, 1972-1997, (3 folders) (Box 1)
        - Memorial remarks and attached background material, 1962, 1976-1996 (Box 2)
        - Photo album, 1972-1992, 2006 (Box 2)
      - Bradlee, Benjamin C., 1956, 1965-2000, (3 folders) (Box 2)
      - Brokaw, Tom, 1978-2004, undated, (2 folders) (Box 2)
      - Brustein, Robert Sanford, 1974-2001, (2 folders) (Box 2)
      - Buckley, William F., Jr., 1967-2007, (2 folders) (Box 2)
      - Burnett, Carol, 1979-1993, 2001-2002 (Box 2)
      - Califano, Joseph A., Jr. (Box 2)
        - 1970-1985, (1 folder) (Box 2)
        - 1986-1994, 2000-circa 2005, (1 folder) (Box 3)
      - Capp, Al, 1970-1978, undated (Box 3)
      - Carter, Jimmy and Rosalynn, 1976-1980, 1998-2002, (2 folders) (Box 3)
      - Cartoonists, 1965-circa 1996, 2002-2006, undated, (2 folders) (Box 3)
      - Clinton, Bill and Hillary Rodham, 1993-2005, (2 folders) (Box 3)
      - Cohen, William, 1978, 1997-1998 (Box 3)
      - Congressional (Box 3)
        - 1959-1989, (4 folders) (Box 3)
        - 1990-1997, undated, (1 folder) (Box 4)
      - Conrad, Paul, 1973-1997, undated, (2 folders) (Box 4)
      - Dickinson, Angie, 1977-2002, undated (Box 4)
      - Durr, Virginia Foster, 1974-1988, 1994-1999 (Box 4)
      - Eisenhower, Dwight D., 1965-1969 (Box 4)
      - Ford, Gerald R. and Betty, 1974-1997, undated, (2 folders) (Box 4)
      - Frost, Robert, 1961 (Box 4)
      - Grace, Princess of Monaco, 1956, 1968, 1974-1982, 1995-2002, (4 folders) (Box 4)
      - Graham, Katharine (Box 4)
        - 1965-1987, (1 folder) (Box 4)
        - 1988-2001, undated, (2 folders) (Box 5)
      - Hanks, Tom, 1999 (Box 5)
      - Hoffman, Irving, 1950, 1957-1958, 1964-1966, 1992, undated See also Container OV 7, Letter; See also Buchwald, Ann, Correspondence (Family, 1950), (3 folders) (Box 5)
      - Humphrey, Hubert H., 1965-1975 (Box 5)
      - Johnson, Lady Bird and Lyndon B., 1964-1966, 1993-1994, 2000-2002, undated (Box 5)
      - Kennedy family (Box 5)
        - General, 1967, undated, (2 folders) (Box 5)
        - Kennedy children, 1969-1971, 1978, 1986, undated (Box 5)
        - Kennedy, Christopher, 1973-1984, 1990-2004 (Box 5)
        - Kennedy, Courtney, 1969-1974, 1980-1990 (Box 5)
        - Kennedy, Edward M. (Edward Moore), 1966-2000, undated (Box 5)
        - Kennedy, Ethel (Box 5)
          - 1957-1969 See also Containers OV 7 and OV 10, Photograph and valentine, (1 folder) (Box 5)
          - 1970-2001, undated, (4 folders) (Box 6)
        - Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1963-1964, 1983 (Box 6)
        - Kennedy, John F., Jr., 1996-1997 (Box 6)
        - Kennedy, Joseph Patrick, 1979-1986 (Box 6)
        - Kennedy, Kerry, 1969, 1987-1996 (Box 7)
        - Kennedy, Maxwell Taylor, 1977-1981, 1989-1996 (Box 7)
        - Kennedy, Michael, 1969, 1980, undated (Box 7)
        - Kennedy, Robert F. (Box 7)
          - Andy Williams tribute recording, 1968-1969, undated (Box 7)
          - General, 1965-1968, undated (Box 7)
          - Memorial, 1968-1978 (Box 7)
        - Kennedy, Robert Francis, Jr., 1969, 1982-1993, 2000 (Box 7)
        - Kennedy, Rory, 1969, 1977-1978, 1999-2004 (Box 7)
        - Kennedy, Rose Fitzgerald, 1968-1976 (Box 7)
        - Lawford, Patricia Kennedy, 1968, 1978, 1984 (Box 7)
        - Onassis, Jacqueline Kennedy, 1975-1989 (Box 7)
        - Schlossberg, Edwin, 1989 (Box 7)
        - Shriver, Eunice Kennedy, 1965-1996, undated See also Container OV 7, Photographs (Box 7)
        - Shriver, Maria, 1970-1971, 1986-1994, undated (Box 7)
        - Shriver, Sargent, 1963-1965, 1977-2004 (Box 7)
        - Shriver children, 1977-1997 (Box 8)
        - Smith, Jean Kennedy, 1970, 1976-1980, 1986-1990, 1996-1998 (Box 8)
        - Townsend, Kathleen Kennedy, 1969-1973, 1980-1982, 1989-2000 (Box 8)
      - Kissinger, Henry, 1973-1982, 2006 (Box 8)
      - Landers, Ann, 1964-1995, undated, (5 folders) (Box 8)
      - Lazar, Irving, 1958, 1968-1994 (Box 8)
      - Lear, Norman, 1981-1994, 2003-2005 (Box 8)
      - Manning, Gordon (Box 8)
        - 1962-1994, (3 folders) (Box 8)
        - 1996-2002, undated, (1 folder) (Box 9)
      - Mazzotta, Jim, 1979-1981 (Box 9)
      - McNamara, Robert S., 1964-1967, 1978-1981, undated (Box 9)
      - Military, 1963-1978, 1991-2002, undated, (2 folders) (Box 9)
      - Mondale, Walter F., 1973-1984, undated (Box 9)
      - Nixon, Richard M., 1968-1974 (Box 9)
      - Phillips, Kyra, 1989-2006, undated, (2 folders) (Box 9)
      - Plimpton, George, 1968-1990, 1999 (Box 9)
      - Powell, Colin, 1992, 2004-2005 (Box 9)
      - Rales, Norman, 1984-2005 (Box 9)
      - Reagan, Ronald, 1981-1982 (Box 9)
      - Rumsfeld, Donald and Joyce, 1975-1986, 2000-2002, (2 folders) (Box 9)
      - Russell, Mark, 1994, undated (Box 9)
      - Schlesinger, Arthur M., Jr., 1946-1947, 1961-1986, 1994-1997 (Box 9)
      - Seuss, Dr., 1974, 1983-1984 (Box 9)
      - Shaw, Irwin, 1963-1986 (Box 9)
      - Shore, Dinah (Box 9)
        - 1976-1980, (1 folder) (Box 9)
        - 1981-1991, undated, (3 folders) (Box 10)
      - Starling, Florence Leola ("Flossie"), 1965, 1985-1996, undated, (6 folders) (Box 10)
      - Steinbeck, John, 1953, 1972 (Box 10)
      - Stevens, George, Jr., 1965-1997, 2005, undated, (2 folders) (Box 10)
      - Styron, William, 1967-1997, undated, (3 folders) (Box 10)
      - Supreme Court, 1964-1986 (Box 10)
      - Todd, Michael, Jr., 1980-1987 (Box 11)
      - Todd, Mike, 1956-1957 (Box 11)
      - Trillin, Calvin, 1983, 1991, 2000 (Box 11)
      - Trudeau, Gary, 1972-1976, 1984-1985, 2002 (Box 11)
      - Trump, Donald, 1988-1989, 1995 (Box 11)
      - Van Buren, Abigail, 1964-1991, (2 folders) (Box 11)
      - Vonnegut, Kurt, 1982-1983 (Box 11)
      - Wallace, Mike, 1970-1982, 1988-2001, undated, (2 folders) (Box 11)
      - White House, 1962-1991, 2002, undated, (2 folders) (Box 11)
      - Williams, Edward Bennett, 1965-1991, undated, (4 folders) (Box 11)
      - Wolper, David L., 1964-1969, 1976-1998, undated, (3 folders) (Box 12)
    - Chronological
      - 1953-1969, (10 folders) (Box 12)
      - 1970-1976, (14 folders) (Box 13)
      - 1977-1980, (13 folders) (Box 14)
      - 1981-1986, (14 folders) (Box 15)
      - 1986-1992, (15 folders) (Box 16)
      - 1992-1997, (13 folders) (Box 17)
      - 1998-2007, undated, (7 folders) (Box 18)
  - Close friends (Box 18)
    - Attwood, William, 1965-1990, undated, (2 folders) (Box 18)
    - Hackney, Lucy and Sheldon, 1976-1995, undated, (5 folders) (Box 18)
    - Harris, Ira, 1974-1998, undated (Box 19)
    - Hix, Al, 1963-1999, undated, (6 folders) (Box 19)
    - Hu, Tommy and Mary, 1986-1996, undated, (2 folders) (Box 19)
    - Marton, Hilda and George, 1966-1996, undated (Box 19)
    - Minow, Newton N., and Josephine Baskin, 1963-2002, undated, (2 folders) (Box 19)
    - Mukasa, Charles J., 1972-2001, (3 folders) (Box 19)
    - Naccache, Ursula, 1965-1996 (Box 20)
    - Nolan, James, 1952, 1964-1989, undated, (2 folders) (Box 20)
    - Pakula, Hannah, 1998-2000, undated, (2 folders) (Box 20)
    - Parrish, Robert (Box 20)
      - 1964-1978, (4 folders) (Box 20)
      - 1979-1994, undated, (10 folders) (Box 21)
    - Rennie, Gwen, 1979-1994, undated (Box 21)
    - Targ, Roslyn and William, 1965-1989 (Box 21)
    - Wood, Joyce Teitz, 1967-1971, 1978-2002 (Box 22)
    - Yoakum, Robert, 1965-1998, undated, (4 folders) (Box 22)
  - Chronological (Box 22)
    - 1947-1957 Nov., (12 folders) (Box 22)
    - 1957 Dec.-1964, (17 folders) (Box 23)
    - 1965-1966 Mar., (16 folders) (Box 24)
    - 1966 Apr.-1967 Sept., (18 folders) (Box 25)
    - 1967 Oct.-1969, (15 folders) (Box 26)
    - 1970-1971 Apr. See also Container OV 8, Scrapbook, (18 folders) (Box 27)
    - 1971 May-1973 July, (17 folders) (Box 28)
    - 1973 Sept.-1976 Mar., (17 folders) (Box 29)
    - 1976 Apr.-1977 Oct., (20 folders) (Box 30)
    - 1977 Nov.-1979 Apr., (21 folders) (Box 31)
    - 1979 May-1980 Nov., (17 folders) (Box 32)
    - 1980 Dec.-1982 Mar., (17 folders) (Box 33)
    - 1982 Apr.-1983 Oct., (20 folders) (Box 34)
    - 1983 Nov.-1985 Apr., (21 folders) (Box 35)
    - 1985 May-1986 Nov., (18 folders) (Box 36)
    - 1986 Dec.-1988 Mar., (16 folders) (Box 37)
    - 1988 Apr.-1989 May, (14 folders) (Box 38)
    - 1989 June-1990 Dec., (12 folders) (Box 39)
    - 1991-1992 Oct., (9 folders) (Box 40)
    - 1992 Nov.-1995 Sept., (10 folders) (Box 41)
    - 1995 Oct.-1997, (11 folders) (Box 42)
    - 1997-1998 Aug., (10 folders) (Box 43)
    - 1998 Sept.-2000 Sept., (11 folders) (Box 44)
    - 2000 Oct.-2001 Aug., (12 folders) (Box 45)
    - 2001 Sept.-2002 Nov., (14 folders) (Box 46)
    - 2002 Dec.-2004 May, (12 folders) (Box 47)
    - 2004 June-2007 Jan., undated, (13 folders) (Box 48)
- Writings, 1948-2006 (Box 49-132)
  The Writings series forms the largest portion of the collection and documents Buchwald’s work as a columnist, novelist, autobiographer, and playwright and documents his many articles, books, columns, memoirs, plays, and screenplays. A nearly complete chronological run of Buchwald’s columns is contained in this series and dates between 1949 and 2006. The columns take the form of newspaper clippings and drafts bearing Buchwald’s edits. Russian translations of Buchwald’s columns as they appeared in Soviet periodicals, especially Prâvda, are also included. These translations date primarily between 1958 and 1969 and were sent to Buchwald by a variety of sources, among them, Radio Free Europe, the United States Information Agency, and a reader named Misha Allen. Material related to Buchwald’s numerous books, most of which are anthologies of his columns and articles, are also contained in this series and are largely documented by correspondence with publishers, friends, and readers, book reviews, and other publishing work product. Buchwald’s memoirs, Leaving Home, I’ll Always Have Paris, and Too Soon to Say Goodbye, are heavily documented in the Writings series and include digital and analog manuscript drafts, letters from readers, and background research. Unpublished works include a collection of letters titled “Read Between the Lines” and an autobiography titled “Revenge is Sweet.” Many of Buchwald’s play scripts and screenplays are also represented in this series, with Sheep on the Runway, which was performed on Broadway from 1969 to 1970, and his first play, No Love Atoll, performed at the University of Southern California Varsity Show in 1948, among the most well documented. Researchers should note additional column drafts and book manuscripts can be found in the Digital File series. Some of Buchwald's earliest writings, including articles written while in the United States Marine Corps and as coursework while at the University of Southern California are found in the Personal File.